Johnothan Christopher Arscott Full Stack Web Developer

| John.Arscott@hotmail.com |

Linkedin:https://www.linkedin.com/in/jca-dev/ GitHub:https://github.com/Jca-Dev

Resume Website: https://jca-dev.github.io/Bootstrap-Resume/

I am an eager Junior Full-Stack Web Developer that's new to the industry, full of motivation and a spongy brain ready to absorb information.

I have strong problem solving skills with great attention to detail.

Being proficient in working with Front End Software Development languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript I have expanded my knowledge base with Back End experience using Python, Django and JavaScript Object Oriented Programming.

My background is mainly customer service experience (11 years) meeting and helping people from all around the world.

I also have 6 years safety critical experience in the rail industry.

Key Skills & Relevant Qualifications

Languages:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Frameworks:

Django, Bootstrap, jQuery, Flask, Materialize CSS

Databases:

PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy

Other:

GIT, GitHub, Microsoft Visual Studio, Balsamiq Wireframes, Heroku, API's, Node.js, Automated testing, Agile, Unit testing, JESTS, CRUD

Work Experience

Metal Fabricator

Carsan - Quebec, Canada

September 2022 to Present

- Following procedure with great attention to detail fabricating metal to form blinds for windows
- Customizing fabrication according to customer requirements
- Fabricating metal, cutting and punching slats and quality control before packing the product

Delivery driver

Amazon – Quebec, Canada

July 2022 to September 2022

• As a delivery driver for amazon I spend most of my time on the road alone delivering packages to customers. Representing amazon I am kind, polite, clean and safe providing the best customer service possible. This includes reading delivery notes and completing customer requests

Train conductor, ticket examiner

Great Western Railway - Devon, England

March 2016 to May 2022

- Absolute responsibility for the safety and time keeping of my train on the railway network
- Working in a team with my Driver, Control, Signalers and Fleet Maintenance to keep the safety and efficiency of my train and the running line
- finding and fixing faults on my train and reporting un-fixable faults
- Making sure my train is clean and safe for my passengers
- Perform revenue duties on the train and assist passengers with extra needs such as a wheelchair user requiring a ramp
- Perform emergency line protection if required on electrified AC DC and non electrified rails
- Use the phonetic alphabet to communicate clearly

Help desk supervisor

Homebase - Devon, England

September 2015 to March 2016.

- Resolve customer complaints and provide excellent customer service to all customers
- Manage customer orders providing information on our products and services
- Lead a team of 3 checkout operators
- Support colleagues within the team to ensure they are performing at their best to delight our customers
- Lead by example through my behaviour and appearance
- Manage the full range of duties by being focused, proactive and delegate to others to ensure everything gets completed on time and to a high standard

Automotive sales, parts and workshop specialist

Torbay Motorcycles ltd - Devon, England

January 2015 to September 2015

- Use of telephone, problem solving and organisational skills were paramount to my success in this role
- Booking in customers into the workshop diary utilizing resources available to maximize profits while exceeding customer expectations
- Educating customers by explaining our services offering and recommending what's best for the customer leading to sales of motorbikes and accessories working toward sales targets
- Managing stock effectively to ensure we had the correct products available to meet demand
- Using my experience I understood our customer base and anticipated their needs

Barman, Waiter, Shop Supervisor, Chef

Haulfryn - Devon, England

May 2014 to January 2015

- This role required prioritization and flexibility where I thrived In making important decisions on a regular basis to meet the needs of customers and staying in line with the company rules & regulations
- Working front of house enabled me to provide an excellent service to delight guests
- Meeting a large range of diverse customers and having multiple job roles in a fast paced environment gave me the experience and keen eye for detail under pressure

Shop Assistant

MARTIN MCOLLS, GILLETS SPAR - Devon, England

November 2012 to July 2014

- Provide excellent customer service by assisting customers and meeting their individual needs
- Responsibility to manage the baking of fresh goods
- Following the company standards, I worked and ensured the safety of our customers and managed stock on the shop floor ensuring goods were available to customers and were well presented
- Being a local shop at times I had to manage conflict situations where underage customers attempted to purchase age restricted goods
- Through excellent listening skills I could understand customer's requirements and provide solutions
- Adhere to cash regulations when retailing goods through the till

Education

Diploma Level 5: Full-Stack Software Development

Feb 2022 – Present 2013

BTEC Level 3: Public Services (C)

2012

BTEC Level 2: Public Services (A*), IT (C)

2012

GCSE: Maths, Physical Education, English, Food Technology, Geography, Science

2011

NVQ: Retail, Work Hazard Awareness, Junior Sports leadership

Most Recent Project:

Restaurant reservation system

GitHub link: https://github.com/Jca-Dev/Reservation_System